simplethemes.net 2015-03-26

# Privacy Policy

### Our Commitment to Your Privacy

This site is owned and operated by Simple Themes, LLC. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. At Simple Themes, LLC, we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe.

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it.

Simple Themes, LLC gathers two types of information about users:

Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to receive our electronic newsletters, to participate in our message boards or forums, to email a friend, and from participation in polls and surveys.

Information Simple Themes, LLC gathers through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites using Google Analytics software. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to better understand the demographics of our audience. Under no circumstances does Simple Themes, LLC divulge any information about an individual user to a third party.

###  Optional Voluntary Information

Simple Themes, LLC Gathers User Information In The Following Processes:

**1\. Electronic newsletters (Dispatches)**

We will offer a free electronic newsletter to users. Simple Themes, LLC gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters at the time of registration.

**2\. Message boards/forums**

Users of the site's Message Boards and Forums must register separately for these services (both are free of charge) in order to post messages, although they needn't register to visit the site. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address.

###  Children

Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent.

###  Usage Tracking

Simple Themes, LLC tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. Simple Themes, LLC does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser).

Simple Themes, LLC sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.

###  Cookies

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Simple Themes, LLC uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above).

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in message boards, forums, polling and surveys.

###  Use of Information

Simple Themes, LLC uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. Simple Themes, LLC never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners.

When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters.

Simple Themes, LLC creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because we don't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

###  Sharing of Information

Simple Themes, LLC will never share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

###  Security

Simple Themes, LLC operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers.

###  Opt-Out Policy

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include:

  * Opting not to register to receive our electronic newsletters
  * Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users

###  Your Consent

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Simple Themes, LLC. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.
